

Ana García del Molino

I am in the final sprint of my Ph.D. at I2R and NTU, Singapore, currently working on Visual Memory and Summarization from First Person View content.

My research interests are in the areas of visual understanding, cognitive vision and personalization.

@ garciadelmolino.github.io

GarciaDelMolino

☑ ana002@ntu.edu.sg

(+65) 8602 1449

Research Experience

🛱 2014-Today

① Ph.D. Candidate

 $\stackrel{\mathsf{a}}{\sim}$ Supervised by Joo-Hwee Lim

- (a) Use of conditional random fields and probabilistic inference for interactive video summarization with diversity and querydriven objectives.
- using LSTM networks, to detect daily activities and learn associations between life
- (a) Use of image quality analysis and semantic retrieval techniques for query-based lifelog summarization.

gifs.com

gifs.com, Zurich

Research Consultant

🛱 June 2017-Sept 2017 A With Michael Gygli

1 Use of a deep ranking model with personalizable input to customize the highlight detection in videos.

- National Inst. of Informatics, Tokyo
- ₿ 2013
- ① Research Intern
- With Shin'ichi Satoh and Xavier Giró-i-Nieto

Extension of the Bag of Words instance search technique by geometric coding and quantization error compensation.

- © UPC Image Processing Group, Barcelona
- ₿ 2012
- Research Intern
- A With Ferran Marqués

Exploration of image processing techniques for object tracking applied to sports.

Education and Skills

PhD. in Cognitive Systems and Visual Computing



School of Computer Science and Engineering [□] 2015-(expected Summer 2019)



BSc. and MSc. in Telecomm Engineering

 TelecommBCN (FTSFTB) 2008-2013

- Native Speaker
- Native Speaker
- # Fluent (TOEFL 103/120)
- Proficient (CEFRL B2.2)
- Beginner (CEFRL A1)

Proficient in Matlab, Python, TensorFlow, OpenCV. Prior experience with Caffe, C++, SQL, HTML, CSS.

U enjoy sailing, the cinema and the opera, playing board games... And I make earrings!

Make the most of your hobbies! I was a sailing instructor in Barcelona the summers of '08 to '12. Causes that matter. I am part of the leadership of the LeanIn Circle "Al Singapore".

Commitment to the community. During my undergrad, I was part of several student associations: Vice-President of the IEEE Barcelona Student Branch in 2011-2013; Member of the School's Evaluation Committee and Board; intern at the International Student Office.

Honors and Awards



SINGA Scholarship # 2015

Award given by A*STAR to international students to pursue their PhD at a Singapore University.



Obra Social "La Caixa" **□** 2014

Private fellowship to support postgraduate studies in North America and Asia-Pacific.

Selected Publications

🗎 Ana Garcia del Molino, Joo-Hwee Lim, and Ah-Hwee Tan. 2018. Predicting Visual Context for Unsupervised Event Segmentation in Continuous Photo-streams. In Proceedings of the 26th ACM international conference on Multimedia (MM '18).

Ana Garcia del Molino and Michael Gygli. 2018. PHD-GIFs: Personalized Highlight Detection for Automatic GIF Creation. In Proceedings of the 26th ACM international conference on Multimedia (MM '18).

🖺 Ana Garcia del Molino, Xavier Boix, Joo-Hwee Lim, and Ah-Hwee Tan. 2017. Active Video Summarization: Customized Summaries via Online Interaction with the User. In AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence.

🗎 Ana Garcia del Molino, Cheston Tan, Joo-Hwee Lim, and Ah-Hwee Tan. 2017. Summarization of Egocentric Videos: A Comprehensive Survey. In IEEE Transactions on Human-Machine Systems, 47(1).

(More in my Scholar profile)